{


"Physics Model Paper" : [
  {
    "question": "Kilo watt hour is the unit of",
    "correct_answer": "energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 horse power is equal to",
    "correct_answer": "746 W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pascal is the SI unit of",
    "correct_answer": "Modulus of elasticity"
  },
  {
    "question": "SI unit of coefficient of thermal conductivity is",
    "correct_answer": "W m\u207b\u00b9 K\u207b\u00b9"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the following which is not a unit of time",
    "correct_answer": "Light year"
  },
  {
    "question": "candela is the SI unit of",
    "correct_answer": "Luminous intensity"
  },
  {
    "question": "kg m s\u207b\u00b9 is the unit of",
    "correct_answer": "Force"
  },
  {
    "question": "unit used to measure nuclear diameters is",
    "correct_answer": "Fermi"
  },
  {
    "question": "parsec is the unit to measure",
    "correct_answer": "distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 KWH is equal to",
    "correct_answer": "36 \u00d7 10\u2075 J"
  },
  {
    "question": "physical quantity having the unit J kg\u207b\u00b9 is",
    "correct_answer": "Latent heat"
  },
  {
    "question": "unit of magnetic induction field B is",
    "correct_answer": "all the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "SI unit of electric intensity is",
    "correct_answer": "H m\u207b\u00b9"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the units of length, mass and time are doubled, the unit of force will be",
    "correct_answer": "unchanged"
  },
  {
    "question": "Derived unit is",
    "correct_answer": "volt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The set of quantities which can form a group of fundamental quantities in any system of measurement is",
    "correct_answer": "All the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "the fundamental unit which is common in CGS and SI is",
    "correct_answer": "Second"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dimensional formula of coefficient of viscosity is",
    "correct_answer": "M\u00b9 L\u207b\u00b9 T\u207b\u00b9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Heat and thermal capacity differ in the dimensions of",
    "correct_answer": "temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "force constant and surface tension have the same dimensions in",
    "correct_answer": "all the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "the pair of physical quantities having the same dimensions is",
    "correct_answer": "Latent heat and gravitational potential"
  },
  {
    "question": "a scalar quantity and a vector quantity having the same dimensions are",
    "correct_answer": "Frequency and velocity gradient"
  },
  {
    "question": "the pair of vector quantities having the same dimensions is",
    "correct_answer": "Thrust and weight"
  },
  {
    "question": "the pair of scalar quantities having the same dimensions is",
    "correct_answer": "Plank's constant and angular momentum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Quantity having units but no dimensions is",
    "correct_answer": "Strain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dimensionless quantity is",
    "correct_answer": "Refractive index"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fundamental quantity which is common in MKS and SI is",
    "correct_answer": "all the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "One shake is equal to",
    "correct_answer": "10\u207b\u2078s"
  },
  {
    "question": "The physical quantity which has dimensional formula as that of \nenergy / mass X length   is",
    "correct_answer": "acceleration"
  },
  {
    "question": "The quantity have negative dimensions in mass is",
    "correct_answer": "Gravitational constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two quantities A and B are related by the relation A/B = m where 'm' is linear\nmass density and A is force. The dimensions of B will be",
    "correct_answer": "Same as that of latent heat"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit of universal gas constant is",
    "correct_answer": "erg/ K"
  },
  {
    "question": "The physical quantity having the dimensions [M\u207b\u00b9 L\u207b\u00b3 T\u00b3 A\u00b2] is",
    "correct_answer": "Electrical conductivity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given that the displacement of an oscillating particle is given by\nY = Asin(Bx + Ct + D). The dimensional formula for 'ABCD' is",
    "correct_answer": "M\u00b0 L T\u207b\u00b9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parsec is the unit of",
    "correct_answer": "Distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "If force F, work W and velocity v are taken as fundamental quantities, then the dimensional formula of time T is",
    "correct_answer": "[W F\u207b\u00b9 v\u207b\u00b9 ]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Light year is a unit of",
    "correct_answer": "Distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnitude of any physical quantity",
    "correct_answer": "Does not depend on the method of measurement"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not a derived unit?",
    "correct_answer": "Electric current"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ratio of the dimensions of Planck's constant and that of the moment of inertia is the dimension of",
    "correct_answer": "Frequency"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SI unit of thermal conductivity is",
    "correct_answer": "W\u207b\u00b9m\u207b\u00b9K\u207b\u00b9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Surface tension has the same dimensions as that of",
    "correct_answer": "spring constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit of magnetic moment is",
    "correct_answer": "Am\u207b\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unit of electrical conductivity is",
    "correct_answer": "mho/m"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two of the following five physical parameters have the same dimensions?\n1) Energy Density\n2) Refractive Index\n3) Dielectric Constant\n4) Young's Modulus\n5) Magnetic Field",
    "correct_answer": "1 and 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The only mechanical quantity which has negative dimension of mass is",
    "correct_answer": "Gravitational Constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is not a unit of Young's modulus?",
    "correct_answer": "Nm\u207b\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SI unit of power is",
    "correct_answer": "watt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Surface tension has the same dimensions as that of",
    "correct_answer": "Spring constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "The dimensions of impulse is",
    "correct_answer": "MLT\u207b\u00b9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the correct statement",
    "correct_answer": "All the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the incorrect statement",
    "correct_answer": "All the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nature of the angular momentum",
    "correct_answer": "Axial"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a scalar quantity?",
    "correct_answer": "Electric current strength"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a scalar quantity",
    "correct_answer": "electric charge"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a physical quantity that has a magnitude but no\ndirection?",
    "correct_answer": "scalar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a vector quantity",
    "correct_answer": "Displacement"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pair containing scalar and vector quantity is",
    "correct_answer": "Electro motive force and force"
  },
  {
    "question": "The set containing only scalar quantities is",
    "correct_answer": "Pole strength, permeability and permittivity"
  },
  {
    "question": "The set containing only vector quantities is",
    "correct_answer": "Magnetic momentum, electric intensity and torque"
  },
  {
    "question": "Angular velocity is",
    "correct_answer": "An axial vector"
  },
  {
    "question": "If we add two vectors of equal magnitudes but in opposite directions, we get",
    "correct_answer": "zero vector"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a vector is along the horizontal direction, its vertical component is",
    "correct_answer": "Zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "A vector is not changed if",
    "correct_answer": "It is slide parallel to itself"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the magnitude of a unit vector?",
    "correct_answer": "Unity"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the minimum number of rectangular components of a vector can be split in space and plane respectively",
    "correct_answer": "3, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The resultant of two forces cannot be exceed",
    "correct_answer": "Algebraic sum of the two forces"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the following pseudo vector is",
    "correct_answer": "Angular momentum"
  },
  {
    "question": "The component of vector is",
    "correct_answer": "Less than or equal to its magnitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Amoung the following pseudo vector is",
    "correct_answer": "Angular momentum"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body moves from one corner of an equilateral triangle of side 10 cm to\n  the same corner along the sides. Then the distance and displacement are respectively",
    "correct_answer": "30 cm & 0 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body moves from A to B with a constant speed of 20 kmph and then from B to A\n  with a constant speed of 30 kmph. Then the average speed of the car is",
    "correct_answer": "24 kmph"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body moves with a speed of 20 kmph in the first 5s and with a \n speed of 30 kmph in the next 5 s. Then, the average speed of the body is",
    "correct_answer": "25 kmph"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body starting from rest and travelling with uniform acceleration has a \n velocity of 40 m/s after 10 second at A. Velocity of the body 4 second before\n it crosses the point A is",
    "correct_answer": "24 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle is moving in a circle in a radius 'r' with a constant speed 'v.\n Then change in velocity after the particle has travelled a distance equal to 1/8th of\n the circumference of the circle is:",
    "correct_answer": "0.785 v"
  },
  {
    "question": "The limiting friction between two bodies in contact is independent of",
    "correct_answer": "The area of surfaces in contact"
  },
  {
    "question": "Equal masses (m each) are attached at the two ends of a string passing over \n two pull leys. Another mass is attached at the centre of the string. \n In order that there is no sag in the string this mass should be",
    "correct_answer": "infinite"
  },
  {
    "question": "The coefficient of static friction between two surfaces depends on",
    "correct_answer": "The shape of the surface in contact"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the mass is rotated in a plane about a\n fixed point, its angular momentum is directed along",
    "correct_answer": "the axis of rotation"
  },
  {
    "question": "A missile is launched with a velocity less than the earth's escape velocity.\n  The sun of its kinetic and potential energy is",
    "correct_answer": "negative"
  },
  {
    "question": "A car moves along a straight line whose motion is given by S= 12t + 3t\u00b2 - 2t\u00b3 \nWhere 'S' is in metres and't' is in seconds.\nThe velocity of the car at the start will be:",
    "correct_answer": "12 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "The velocity of a body as a function of time is V = t\u00b3- 6t\u00b2 + 10t +4. \nSet the acceleration of a body in increasing order at given times\n  i)t =Osec      ii) t = 1sec     iii) t=5 sec",
    "correct_answer": "ii,i,iii"
  },
  {
    "question": "Distance travelled by a body is given by\n2S=10t + 5t\u00b2m. The acceleration of the body is",
    "correct_answer": "5 m/s\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a projectile the range and maximum height are equal. The angle of projection is",
    "correct_answer": "75\u00b0"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a body travels 30 m in an interval of 2 s and 50 m in the next interval of 2 s,\n then the acceleration of the body is",
    "correct_answer": "10 m/s\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The kinetic friction is always:",
    "correct_answer": "Greater than rolling friction"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angle which the rough inclined plane makes with the horizontal\n  when the body placed on it just starts sliding down is called",
    "correct_answer": "Angle of friction"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rolling friction is:",
    "correct_answer": "Less than static friction"
  },
  {
    "question": "A force of 98 N is required to pull a body of mass 100 kg over ice.\n  The coefficient of friction is:",
    "correct_answer": "0.1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A car turns on a slippery road at a constant speed of 10 m/s. If the coefficient \nof friction is 0.5, the minimum radius of the are in meter in which the car turns",
    "correct_answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "question": "A car moves along a straight line whose motion is given by S= 12t + 3t\u00b2 - 2t\u00b3 \nWhere 'S' is in metres and't' is in seconds.\nThe velocity of the car at the start will be:",
    "correct_answer": "12 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "The velocity of a body as a function of time is V = t\u00b3- 6t\u00b2 + 10t +4. \nSet the acceleration of a body in increasing order at given times\n  i)t =Osec      ii) t = 1sec     iii) t=5 sec",
    "correct_answer": "ii,i,iii"
  },
  {
    "question": "Distance travelled by a body is given by\n2S=10t + 5t\u00b2m. The acceleration of the body is",
    "correct_answer": "5 m/s\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a projectile the range and maximum height are equal. The angle of projection is",
    "correct_answer": "75\u00b0"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a body travels 30 m in an interval of 2 s and 50 m in the next interval of 2 s,\n then the acceleration of the body is",
    "correct_answer": "10 m/s\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The kinetic friction is always:",
    "correct_answer": "Greater than rolling friction"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angle which the rough inclined plane makes with the horizontal\n  when the body placed on it just starts sliding down is called",
    "correct_answer": "Angle of friction"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rolling friction is:",
    "correct_answer": "Less than static friction"
  },
  {
    "question": "A force of 98 N is required to pull a body of mass 100 kg over ice.\n  The coefficient of friction is:",
    "correct_answer": "0.1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A car turns on a slippery road at a constant speed of 10 m/s. If the coefficient \nof friction is 0.5, the minimum radius of the are in meter in which the car turns",
    "correct_answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body starting with a velocity 'v' returns to its initial position after 't' second with the same speed, along the same line. Acceleration of the particle is",
    "correct_answer": "-2v/t"
  },
  {
    "question": "The velocity of body moving along the X-axis is given by v= 4t - 2.5t\u00b2. Its acceleration after 3 s is",
    "correct_answer": "-11 cm/s\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body projected up with a velocity 'u' reaches a height 'h'. To reach double the height, it must be projected up with a velocity of",
    "correct_answer": "\u221a2\u00b5"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body dropped from a height reaches the ground in 5s. The velocity with which it reaches the ground is",
    "correct_answer": "29 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body is thrown up with a velocity 'u' to reach a height 'h'. When the velocity is half the initial velocity, its height from the top point of projection is",
    "correct_answer": "h/4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A child weighing 25 kg slides down a rope hanging from a branch of a tall tree.\n If the force of friction acting against him is 2 N. What is the child's acceleration",
    "correct_answer": "8 m/s\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A fireman weighing 80 kg slides down a pole. If the resting force of friction\n is a constant 720 N, his acceleration measured in m/s\u00b2",
    "correct_answer": "0.9"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body of mass 10 kg slides along a rough horizontal surface. The coefficient of friction is 1/\u221a3. Taking g = 10 m/S\u00b2, the least force which acts at an angle of 30\u00b0 to the horizontal is",
    "correct_answer": "50/\u221a3  N"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 60 kg body is pushed with just enough force to start it moving across a floor and the same force continues to act afterwards. The coefficient of static and sliding frictions are 0.5 and 0.4 respectively. The acceleration of the body is",
    "correct_answer": "1 m/s\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body sliding down a rough inclined plane which makes angle of 30\u00b0 with the\nhorizontal. If the coefficient of friction is 0.26, the acceleration is",
    "correct_answer": "2.78"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body is falling freely from a height of 78.4 m. Its velocity on reaching ground is\n(Given that g =9.8m/s\u00b2)",
    "correct_answer": "39.2 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum height reached by a ball thrown at an angle 60\u00b0 to the horizontal with an initial velocity 9.8 m/s is (given that g-9.8 m/s\u00b2)",
    "correct_answer": "3.675 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a body is projected vertically up with a velocity 'u' and acceleration due to\ngravity 'g' then them of flight is",
    "correct_answer": "2u/g"
  },
  {
    "question": "The initial velocity of a body projected upwards from the ground reaches maximum height of metres is (given that g= 9.8 m/s\u00b2)",
    "correct_answer": "14 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aero plane is flying horizontally at an altitude of 49m with a velocity of 200ms^-1\nWhen it is just above the target a bomb is dropped. The bomb touches the ground missing the target at a horizontal distance of (Assume g = 9.8 ms\u00b2)",
    "correct_answer": "632.4m"
  },
  {
    "question": "A good lubricant should be highly",
    "correct_answer": "Both 1 & 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Theoretically which of the following are best lubricants",
    "correct_answer": "Gases"
  },
  {
    "question": "When moving body is suddenly stopped",
    "correct_answer": "Tyres of the vehicles burst"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sand is dusted to the railway tracks during rainy season to",
    "correct_answer": "Increase friction"
  },
  {
    "question": "With increase of temperature, the frictional force acting between two surfaces",
    "correct_answer": "decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body is falling freely from a height of 78.4 m. Its velocity on reaching ground is\n(Given that g =9.8m/s\u00b2)",
    "correct_answer": "39.2 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum height reached by a ball thrown at an angle 60\u00b0 to the horizontal with an initial velocity 9.8 m/s is (given that g-9.8 m/s\u00b2)",
    "correct_answer": "3.675 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a body is projected vertically up with a velocity 'u' and acceleration due to\ngravity 'g' then them of flight is",
    "correct_answer": "2u/g"
  },
  {
    "question": "The initial velocity of a body projected upwards from the ground reaches maximum height of metres is (given that g= 9.8 m/s\u00b2)",
    "correct_answer": "14 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aero plane is flying horizontally at an altitude of 49m with a velocity of 200ms^-1\nWhen it is just above the target a bomb is dropped. The bomb touches the ground missing the target at a horizontal distance of (Assume g = 9.8 ms\u00b2)",
    "correct_answer": "632.4m"
  },
  {
    "question": "A good lubricant should be highly",
    "correct_answer": "Both 1 & 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Theoretically which of the following are best lubricants",
    "correct_answer": "Gases"
  },
  {
    "question": "When moving body is suddenly stopped",
    "correct_answer": "Tyres of the vehicles burst"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sand is dusted to the railway tracks during rainy season to",
    "correct_answer": "Increase friction"
  },
  {
    "question": "With increase of temperature, the frictional force acting between two surfaces",
    "correct_answer": "decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Work is said to be done by a force",
    "correct_answer": "If the magnitude of the force is not equal to zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "Work is always done on a body when",
    "correct_answer": "It experience an increase in energy through a mechanical influence"
  },
  {
    "question": "A block of mass 'm' is pulled by a force 'F\u00b0 on a level surface through a distance 'S' then",
    "correct_answer": "The work done on the body against gravitational force is zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is incorrect?",
    "correct_answer": "Potential energy arising from attractive forces is always positive"
  },
  {
    "question": "The negative of the work done by the conservative internal forces on a system equals\n the change in",
    "correct_answer": "Potential energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the following choose the wrong statement?",
    "correct_answer": "Work done by a conservative force is independent of the path"
  },
  {
    "question": "There will be increase in potential energy of the system if work is done upon the\n system by",
    "correct_answer": "Weight of the person lifting it"
  },
  {
    "question": "A box is lifted the floor the floor and kept on the table. The work done on the box \n depends on",
    "correct_answer": "Weight of the box"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nature of graph for force-displacement curve for a body projected\n vertically upwards?",
    "correct_answer": "Straight line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Area under the force-displacement curve gives",
    "correct_answer": "Acceleration"
  },
  {
    "question": "Work is said to be done by a force",
    "correct_answer": "If the magnitude of the force is not equal to zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "Work is always done on a body when",
    "correct_answer": "It experience an increase in energy through a mechanical influence"
  },
  {
    "question": "A block of mass 'm' is pulled by a force 'F\u00b0 on a level surface through a distance 'S' then",
    "correct_answer": "The work done on the body against gravitational force is zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is incorrect?",
    "correct_answer": "Potential energy arising from attractive forces is always positive"
  },
  {
    "question": "The negative of the work done by the conservative internal forces on a system equals\n the change in",
    "correct_answer": "Potential energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the following choose the wrong statement?",
    "correct_answer": "Work done by a conservative force is independent of the path"
  },
  {
    "question": "There will be increase in potential energy of the system if work is done upon the\n system by",
    "correct_answer": "Weight of the person lifting it"
  },
  {
    "question": "A box is lifted the floor the floor and kept on the table. The work done on the box \n depends on",
    "correct_answer": "Weight of the box"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nature of graph for force-displacement curve for a body projected\n vertically upwards?",
    "correct_answer": "Straight line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Area under the force-displacement curve gives",
    "correct_answer": "Acceleration"
  },
  {
    "question": "A force does not perform any work if",
    "correct_answer": "None of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under the action of a constant force, a particle is experiencing a constant acceleration. The\npower is",
    "correct_answer": "Increasing uniformly with time"
  },
  {
    "question": "The work done by a force on a body does not depend upon",
    "correct_answer": "The initial velocity of the body"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ball is thrown vertically upwards in free space. Its total mechanical energy",
    "correct_answer": "Remains constant through out of the motion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is incorrect?",
    "correct_answer": "Kinetic energy may be zero, positive or negative"
  },
  {
    "question": "The kinetic energy acquired by a body of mass 'm' after travelling a fixed distance \n from rest under the action a constant force is",
    "correct_answer": "Independent of mass m"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bullet is fired from a rifle. As a result the Rifle recoils. The kinetic energy of\n the rifle as Compared to that of bullet is",
    "correct_answer": "Less"
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the pair of quantities related similarly as work and force",
    "correct_answer": "Electrical potential and intensity"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a paragraph is plotted between momentum and kinetic energy, then shape of \n the graph is",
    "correct_answer": "Parabola"
  },
  {
    "question": "The slope of kinetic energy-displacement curve of a body in motion will be",
    "correct_answer": "Directly proportional to its acceleration"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle is in SHM. Then the graph of its acceleration as a function of displacement is",
    "correct_answer": "straight with negative slope"
  },
  {
    "question": "In simple pendulum is iron bob is replaced by wooden bob of same mass then its time period",
    "correct_answer": "remains same"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time period of loaded spring on the earth is 6 seconds. The time period of the \n loaded spring on the moon is",
    "correct_answer": "6\u221a6s"
  },
  {
    "question": "In SHM at the equilibrium position",
    "correct_answer": "Velocity is maximum"
  },
  {
    "question": "The motion which is not harmonic",
    "correct_answer": "Motion of a planet around the sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "which of the following equations of motion represents SHM",
    "correct_answer": "accelerati on = -k(x + a)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body executing SHM, then the total energy of the body is",
    "correct_answer": "Proportional to its square of amplitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the displacements of the particle is SHM from the mean position is 4 cm, \n the force acting on the particle is 6 N. Then the force acting on the \n particle when its displacement is 6 cm from the mean position is",
    "correct_answer": "9 N"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle is executing SHM and is described by y = A sin \u03c9t. \n The maximum acceleration in this motion is",
    "correct_answer": "A\u03c9\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two simple pendulums oscillate simultaneously from the mean positions. The first \n pendulum made 20 oscillations in certain time in which the second pendulum made 25\n  oscillations. Then the ratio of the lengths of the pendulums is",
    "correct_answer": "25:16"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body executing S.H.M. has a maximum velocity of 1 and a maximum acceleration of 4. Its amplitude in meter's is",
    "correct_answer": "0.25"
  },
  {
    "question": "The equation of motion of particle executing\nSHM is a + 16\u03c0\u00b2x =0. In this equation 'a' is the linear acceleration in m/s\u00b2, of the particle at a displacement x in meters. The time period of SHM, in seconds is",
    "correct_answer": "0.5"
  },
  {
    "question": "If two bodies of same mass are executing S.H.M. with frequencies in the ratio 1: 2 and amplitudes in the ratio 2:3 then the ratio of their total energies is",
    "correct_answer": "1:9"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time period of a light loaded spring is 3.5 seconds. On changing the load by 1kg, the period decreases by 0.5 seconds. The initial load on the spring is",
    "correct_answer": "3 (10/13) kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle is executing simple harmonic motion with an amplitude of 4cm. At the mean position the velocity of the particle is 10 cm/s. The distance of the particle from the\nmean position when its speed becomes 5cm/s is",
    "correct_answer": "2\u221a3cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle executes simple harmonic motion with a period of Ts and amplitude A m. The\nshortest time it takes to reach point A/\u221a2m from its mean position in seconds is",
    "correct_answer": "T/8"
  },
  {
    "question": "A simple pendulum performs SHM about \u00d7=0 with an amplitude 'a', and time period 'T', The speed of the pendulum at x = a/2 will be",
    "correct_answer": "\u221a3\u03c0a/T"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle of mass 0.5 kg executes a SHM under a force F = -(50N/m)x. If it crosses the Centre of oscillation with a speed of 10 m/s, find the amplitude of the motion",
    "correct_answer": "1 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle of mass 200 g executes a SHM. The restoring force provided by a spring of spring constant 80 N/m. Then its time period is,",
    "correct_answer": "0.31 s"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the velocity of the particle in SHM if the frequency of the particle is 7 Hz and amplitude is 0.2 m, when the displacement is 0.1 m",
    "correct_answer": "7.621 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body executing S.H.M. has a maximum velocity of 1 and a maximum acceleration of 4. Its amplitude in meter's is",
    "correct_answer": "0.25"
  },
  {
    "question": "The equation of motion of particle executing\nSHM is a + 16\u03c0\u00b2x =0. In this equation 'a' is the linear acceleration in m/s\u00b2, of the particle at a displacement x in meters. The time period of SHM, in seconds is",
    "correct_answer": "0.5"
  },
  {
    "question": "If two bodies of same mass are executing S.H.M. with frequencies in the ratio 1: 2 and amplitudes in the ratio 2:3 then the ratio of their total energies is",
    "correct_answer": "1:9"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time period of a light loaded spring is 3.5 seconds. On changing the load by 1kg, the period decreases by 0.5 seconds. The initial load on the spring is",
    "correct_answer": "3 (10/13) kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle is executing simple harmonic motion with an amplitude of 4cm. At the mean position the velocity of the particle is 10 cm/s. The distance of the particle from the\nmean position when its speed becomes 5cm/s is",
    "correct_answer": "2\u221a3cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle executes simple harmonic motion with a period of Ts and amplitude A m. The\nshortest time it takes to reach point A/\u221a2m from its mean position in seconds is",
    "correct_answer": "T/8"
  },
  {
    "question": "A simple pendulum performs SHM about \u00d7=0 with an amplitude 'a', and time period 'T', The speed of the pendulum at x = a/2 will be",
    "correct_answer": "\u221a3\u03c0a/T"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle of mass 0.5 kg executes a SHM under a force F = -(50N/m)x. If it crosses the Centre of oscillation with a speed of 10 m/s, find the amplitude of the motion",
    "correct_answer": "1 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle of mass 200 g executes a SHM. The restoring force provided by a spring of spring constant 80 N/m. Then its time period is,",
    "correct_answer": "0.31 s"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the velocity of the particle in SHM if the frequency of the particle is 7 Hz and amplitude is 0.2 m, when the displacement is 0.1 m",
    "correct_answer": "7.621 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle is performing SHM has an amplitude of 0.2 m and has a period of 2 seconds, then its velocity at mean position is",
    "correct_answer": "0.63 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "The simple pendulum is of length 50 cm. Then its period of oscillation is",
    "correct_answer": "1.42 s"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time period of simple pendulum of length 50 cm is 1.41 s. Then its value of 'g' is",
    "correct_answer": "9.929 m/s^-2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A tuning fork vibrates with a frequency of 130 Hz with an amplitude of 3 mm. Then its maximum velocity is",
    "correct_answer": "2.45 m/s"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle executing SHM with amplitude 'A'. If the maximum velocity is 'v', then the\nmaximum acceleration is",
    "correct_answer": "v\u00b2/A"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle executing SHM along a straight line with diameter 6cm.\nWhen the displacement is 1cm, its velocity is numerically equal to acceleration. The period of the particle is",
    "correct_answer": "2\u03c0/\u221a8"
  },
  {
    "question": "The amplitude of a body executing SHM is 5m. If the velocity of the body at the mean position is 628 m/s, its time period is,",
    "correct_answer": "\u00bd s"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ratio of frequencies of two pendulums are 2:3, then their lengths are in the ratio",
    "correct_answer": "9/4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum acceleration of a simple pendulum is doubled, when",
    "correct_answer": "The amplitude id doubled"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function sin\u00b2 \u03c9t represents",
    "correct_answer": "a periodic, but not SHM with period of \u03c0/\u03c9"
  },
  {
    "question": "The necessary and sufficient condition for SHM is",
    "correct_answer": "Proportionality between acceleration and displacement from equilibrium position"
  },
  {
    "question": "The amplitude of a simple pendulum oscillating in air decreases with time, there will be",
    "correct_answer": "Loss in energy which dissipates heat energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the pendulum is making SHM and passes through mean position it will have",
    "correct_answer": "Maximum KE and minimum PE"
  },
  {
    "question": "A mass 'm' is suspended to a spring. The spring is cut into two halves then the mass ratio of frequency of vibration to the original frequency is",
    "correct_answer": "\u221a2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle executes SHM with a period of 8s and amplitude 4cm of maximum speed in cm/s is",
    "correct_answer": "p"
  },
  {
    "question": "A particle describes uniform circular motion with uniform angular velocity then its projection on any diameter of uniform circular path",
    "correct_answer": "describes a SHM"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a SHM the factor is",
    "correct_answer": "amplitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "A girl swings on cradle in a sitting position. If she stands what happens to the time period of girl and the cradle",
    "correct_answer": "The period decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body of mass 5 x 10\u00b3 kg is making SHM with amplitude 1x10^-1 m with velocity 1ms^-1 Its velocity will be half at displacement of",
    "correct_answer": "5\u221a3\u00d710^-3m"
  },
  {
    "question": "The amplitude of simple pendulum is 4x10^-2m. The KE and PE will equal at a distance from the equilibrium position of",
    "correct_answer": "2\u221a2\u00d710^-2 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "Frequency range of audible range",
    "correct_answer": "20 - 20 kHz"
  },
  {
    "question": "The waves in which the particles of the medium vibrate in a direction\nperpendicular to the direction of the wave motion is known as",
    "correct_answer": "Transverse wave"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a wave travels through a medium",
    "correct_answer": "Energy is transfered at a constant speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "When sound travels through air, the air particles",
    "correct_answer": "Vibrate along the direction of wave Propagation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a musical sound?",
    "correct_answer": "Wavelength"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound travels through",
    "correct_answer": "Solids"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound waves are",
    "correct_answer": "Longitudinal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will remain unchanged when a sound wave travels in air or\n in water?",
    "correct_answer": "Frequency"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the intensity of sound is double, the intensity level will increase by nearly",
    "correct_answer": "dB"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ultrasonic waves can be detected by",
    "correct_answer": "Kundt's tube"
  },
  {
    "question": "Decibel is a",
    "correct_answer": "Unit of intensity"
  },
  {
    "question": "To raise the pitch of a stringed musical instrument the player can",
    "correct_answer": "Tighten the string"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pitch of sound depends on",
    "correct_answer": "Frequency"
  },
  {
    "question": "Beats occur because of",
    "correct_answer": "Interference"
  },
  {
    "question": "When two sound waves are superimposed, beats are produced when they have",
    "correct_answer": "Nearly different frequencies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Doppler effect is applicable for",
    "correct_answer": "Both light and sound waves"
  },
  {
    "question": "The loudness of a sound upon",
    "correct_answer": "Amplitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pitch of sound depends upon",
    "correct_answer": "periodically and regularity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Quality of sound depends upon",
    "correct_answer": "Amplitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sweetness of a sound depends upon",
    "correct_answer": "frequency"
  },
  {
    "question": "Decibel is a",
    "correct_answer": "Unit of intensity"
  },
  {
    "question": "To raise the pitch of a stringed musical instrument the player can",
    "correct_answer": "Tighten the string"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pitch of sound depends on",
    "correct_answer": "Frequency"
  },
  {
    "question": "Beats occur because of",
    "correct_answer": "Interference"
  },
  {
    "question": "When two sound waves are superimposed, beats are produced when they have",
    "correct_answer": "Nearly different frequencies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Doppler effect is applicable for",
    "correct_answer": "Both light and sound waves"
  },
  {
    "question": "The loudness of a sound upon",
    "correct_answer": "Amplitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pitch of sound depends upon",
    "correct_answer": "periodically and regularity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Quality of sound depends upon",
    "correct_answer": "Amplitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sweetness of a sound depends upon",
    "correct_answer": "frequency"
  },
  {
    "question": "A source of sound and an observer are moving away from each other. The apparent pitch will",
    "correct_answer": "Decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound energy is converted into electrical energy to",
    "correct_answer": "Microphone"
  },
  {
    "question": "The walls of the halls built for music concerts should be",
    "correct_answer": "absorb sound"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit to compare the sound energy level is",
    "correct_answer": "Decibel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The intensity of sound produced by A is 1000 times greater than B. Then the difference in the intensity level is",
    "correct_answer": "30 dB"
  },
  {
    "question": "The greater the density of medium",
    "correct_answer": "The louder is the sound"
  },
  {
    "question": "The intensity of sound varies with",
    "correct_answer": "square of excess pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 'zero point' of the scale of loudness is",
    "correct_answer": "Threshold of hearing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Absorption coefficient can be measured by",
    "correct_answer": "Microphone"
  },
  {
    "question": "Absorption coefficient is",
    "correct_answer": "Ratio of energies"
  },
  {
    "question": "A source of sound and an observer are moving away from each other. The apparent pitch will",
    "correct_answer": "Decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound energy is converted into electrical energy to",
    "correct_answer": "Microphone"
  },
  {
    "question": "The walls of the halls built for music concerts should be",
    "correct_answer": "absorb sound"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit to compare the sound energy level is",
    "correct_answer": "Decibel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The intensity of sound produced by A is 1000 times greater than B. Then the difference in the intensity level is",
    "correct_answer": "30 dB"
  },
  {
    "question": "The greater the density of medium",
    "correct_answer": "The louder is the sound"
  },
  {
    "question": "The intensity of sound varies with",
    "correct_answer": "square of excess pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 'zero point' of the scale of loudness is",
    "correct_answer": "Threshold of hearing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Absorption coefficient can be measured by",
    "correct_answer": "Microphone"
  },
  {
    "question": "Absorption coefficient is",
    "correct_answer": "Ratio of energies"
  },
  {
    "question": "A small amount of mercury is at the bottom of a tube of height 4.2 m closed at its two ends. It is turned up and down 21 times. If specific heat of mercury is 0.03 cal gm^-1\u00b0C^-1, g=10ms^-2? and J=4.2J/cal. Temperature of mercury increases by",
    "correct_answer": "21\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ice block at 0\u00b0C falls from rest from contain height. If 0.1% of ice melts on reaching the ground, the height from which it is released (g=10ms^-2,L=80cal/gm,J=4.2J/cal)",
    "correct_answer": "33.6 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bullet of mass 4.2 grams is moving at certain velocity. If all its KE is converted to heat, the amount of energy liberated is 20 cal. Then initial velocity of that bullet is",
    "correct_answer": "200 ms^-1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A lead bullet just melts when stopped by an obstacle. Assuming that 2/7th of the heat is\nabsorbed by the obstacle. If initial temperature is 27\u00b0C, melting point of lead is 327\u00b0C, specific heat = 0.03 cal/gm \u00b0C, latent heat of fusion of lead = 6 cal/gm and J=4.2J/cal, velocity of that bullet is",
    "correct_answer": "420 ms^-1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A block of ice at 0\u00b0C whose mass is initially 21 Kg slides along a horizontal surface starting with an initial velocity of 2 ms-1 and comes to rest. The ice melted as a result of friction between the block and the table is",
    "correct_answer": "1/8 gm"
  },
  {
    "question": "A lead bullet strikes against a steel plate with a velocity of 210 ms-1. If the bullet falls dead after the impact, and the heat produced is shared equally between the bullet and the target, rise in temperature is two of the bullet is (specific heat 0.03 CGS units)",
    "correct_answer": "87.50C"
  },
  {
    "question": "A drilling machine is used to drill a hole in a 10 Kg metal block. Power of the dilling machine is 1 KW and it is used for 5 minutes. If 40% of the work done by the drilling machine is converted into heat in the metal block, the rise in its temperature is (specific heat = 0.115 cal gm^-1\u00b0 C^-1 and J=4.175 J/cal)",
    "correct_answer": "25\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "question": "A water fall is 84 m high. Assuming that 50% of K.E of falling water converts into heat, rise in temperature of water on reaching the ground will be",
    "correct_answer": "0.098\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "question": "When I mole of monoatomic gas is mixed with B moles of a diatomic gas. Then adiabatic exponent of the mixture is",
    "correct_answer": "13/9"
  },
  {
    "question": "The amount of work done by 0.2 mole of gas at 27\u00b0C. When it expands to double its volume at constant pressure is",
    "correct_answer": "120 cal"
  },
  {
    "question": "A small amount of mercury is at the bottom of a tube of height 4.2 m closed at its two ends. It is turned up and down 21 times. If specific heat of mercury is 0.03 cal gm^-1\u00b0C^-1, g=10ms^-2? and J=4.2J/cal. Temperature of mercury increases by",
    "correct_answer": "21\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ice block at 0\u00b0C falls from rest from contain height. If 0.1% of ice melts on reaching the ground, the height from which it is released (g=10ms^-2,L=80cal/gm,J=4.2J/cal)",
    "correct_answer": "33.6 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bullet of mass 4.2 grams is moving at certain velocity. If all its KE is converted to heat, the amount of energy liberated is 20 cal. Then initial velocity of that bullet is",
    "correct_answer": "200 ms^-1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A lead bullet just melts when stopped by an obstacle. Assuming that 2/7th of the heat is\nabsorbed by the obstacle. If initial temperature is 27\u00b0C, melting point of lead is 327\u00b0C, specific heat = 0.03 cal/gm \u00b0C, latent heat of fusion of lead = 6 cal/gm and J=4.2J/cal, velocity of that bullet is",
    "correct_answer": "420 ms^-1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A block of ice at 0\u00b0C whose mass is initially 21 Kg slides along a horizontal surface starting with an initial velocity of 2 ms-1 and comes to rest. The ice melted as a result of friction between the block and the table is",
    "correct_answer": "1/8 gm"
  },
  {
    "question": "A lead bullet strikes against a steel plate with a velocity of 210 ms-1. If the bullet falls dead after the impact, and the heat produced is shared equally between the bullet and the target, rise in temperature is two of the bullet is (specific heat 0.03 CGS units)",
    "correct_answer": "87.50C"
  },
  {
    "question": "A drilling machine is used to drill a hole in a 10 Kg metal block. Power of the dilling machine is 1 KW and it is used for 5 minutes. If 40% of the work done by the drilling machine is converted into heat in the metal block, the rise in its temperature is (specific heat = 0.115 cal gm^-1\u00b0 C^-1 and J=4.175 J/cal)",
    "correct_answer": "25\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "question": "A water fall is 84 m high. Assuming that 50% of K.E of falling water converts into heat, rise in temperature of water on reaching the ground will be",
    "correct_answer": "0.098\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "question": "When I mole of monoatomic gas is mixed with B moles of a diatomic gas. Then adiabatic exponent of the mixture is",
    "correct_answer": "13/9"
  },
  {
    "question": "The amount of work done by 0.2 mole of gas at 27\u00b0C. When it expands to double its volume at constant pressure is",
    "correct_answer": "120 cal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Work done on heating one mole of Helium adiabatically through 00C is W. Then the\nwork done on heating three moles of hydrogen adiabatically through the same change in temperature is",
    "correct_answer": "5 W"
  },
  {
    "question": "One mole of oxygen is heated at contar pressure from 00C. The amount of heat that should be given to double its volume at tne same pressure is (Cp=0.2 cal gm^-1 K^-1)",
    "correct_answer": "1747.2 cal"
  },
  {
    "question": "A mono atomic gas at 170C is suddenly compressed to 1/8 of its original volume.\nThen its final temperature is",
    "correct_answer": "887\u00b0c"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 0.2 Kg steel ball falls from a height of 30 m and bounces to a height of 9m. If all the KE lost is converted to heat, and is absorbed by the ball, rise in temperature of the ball is (take g=10ms^-2 and specific heat of steel=0.1 CGS units)",
    "correct_answer": "0.5\u00b0c"
  },
  {
    "question": "One gram mole of a perfect gas at 1000C expands isothermally until its volume is doubled. Then the amount of work done is about (R=2 cal mol^-1 and J-4.2J/cal)",
    "correct_answer": "2172 J"
  },
  {
    "question": "The molar specific heat of a gas at constant volume is 24J mol^-1 k^-1. Then change in its internal energy if one mole of such gas is heated at constant volume from 10\u00b0C to 30\u00b0C is",
    "correct_answer": "480J"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a certain process 5 Kcal of heat is supplied to the system and the system does\n6000J of work. If the initial internal energy of the System is 37KJ then final value of its\ninternal energy",
    "correct_answer": "52KJ"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ideal gas goes from state A to B as shown. Then work done by the gas during this process is",
    "correct_answer": "Zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "When 1 gm of water at 100\u00b0C is completely converted to steam at 100\u00b0C, occupies\n1650CC. The increase in the internal energy of the molecules is \n(take the pressure = 10^5 Pa, L=540 cal/gm and J=4.2 J/cal)",
    "correct_answer": "2103J"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the adiabatic expansion of a gas volume increases by 5%. If \u03b3 =3/2, the percentage change in pressure is",
    "correct_answer": "-7.5%"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gas expands from 25 lit to 75 lit. at a constant pressure of 2 atm.\n(1 atm= 10^5 Nm^-2). Then work done by the gas during this expansion is",
    "correct_answer": "10 KJ"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gas mixture consists of 4gm of Helium and 32gm of oxygen. Then the ratio of specific heats of the mixture (Cp/Cy) is",
    "correct_answer": "3/2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Certain quantity of heat is supplied to a monoatomic ideal gas which expands at constant pressure. The percentage of heat that goes into work done by the gas is",
    "correct_answer": "40%"
  },
  {
    "question": "The temperature of 5 moles of a gas which was heated at constant. volume was changed from 10\u00b0C to 20\u00b0C. The change in internal energy is found to be 80J. Then heat capacity of the gas at constant volume is",
    "correct_answer": "8 JK^-1"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an adiabatic expansion of 2 moles of a gas, the change in internal energy is equal to -84 J. The work done during this process is",
    "correct_answer": "84 J"
  },
  {
    "question": "A certain gas is found to obey PV\u03b3 during adiabatic change such that \u03b3 =3/21. If T is initial absolute temperature of the gas and the gas is compressed to half of its volume, its final temperature is",
    "correct_answer": "\u221a2T"
  },
  {
    "question": "If R is the universal gas constant, the amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of 2 moles of an ideal monoatomic gas from 0\u00b0C to 100\u00b0C when no work is done is",
    "correct_answer": "300R"
  },
  {
    "question": "The temperature of 100gm of water is to be raised from 24\u00b0C to 90\u00b0C by adding steam to it. Then mass of steam required for the purpose is",
    "correct_answer": "12gm"
  },
  {
    "question": "A container is divided into two equal portions. One portion contains an ideal gas at certain pressure and temperature while the other portion is a perfect vacuum. If a hole is opened between the two portions, the change in energy of the gas is",
    "correct_answer": "Zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "The specific heat at constant volume for a monoatomic gas is 0.075 k cal kg^-1  k^-1  and its gram molecular specific heat is 3cal mo^-1  k^-1 . Then mass of one atom of that gas is\n(Avogadro's number = 6x10\u00b2\u00b3 molecules /mole)",
    "correct_answer": "6.67\u00d710^-23 gm"
  },
  {
    "question": "The density of air at N.T.P. is 1.293 gm/lit. If the pressure is tripled keeping its temperature constant its density becomes",
    "correct_answer": "3.87 gm/ltr"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Vessel containing 10 liter of air under a pressure of 1 MPa is connected to a 4litre empty vessel. The final air pressure in the vessel assuming that the process is isothermal",
    "correct_answer": "5/7 MPa"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Vessel containing 9 litres of an ideal gas at 760 mm pressure is connected to an evacuated 9 litre vessel. The resultant pressure is",
    "correct_answer": "380 mm"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what temperature will the volume of gas be twice the volume at 27\u00b0C at a given pressure",
    "correct_answer": "327\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "question": "At 0\u00b0 C temperature and 1 atmospheric pressure a given mass of gas occupies a volume of 273cc. Its volume at the same pressure and at 50\u00b0 C is",
    "correct_answer": "323cc"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressure of a gas is increased four times and its absolute temperature two times. The ratio of its final volume to its initial volume is",
    "correct_answer": "1:2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The volume of a gas at 27\u00b0C and 2 atmospheric pressure is 2 litres. If the pressure is doubled and absolute temperature is made half, the new volume of gas is",
    "correct_answer": "500 ml"
  },
  {
    "question": "At 20\u00b0C temperature and 1 atmosphere\npressure a gas has a volume of 293 ml. Its volume at NTP is",
    "correct_answer": "273cc"
  },
  {
    "question": "The volume of a gas is 5 litres at NTP, what will be its volume at 273\u00b0C and at a pressure of four atmospheres",
    "correct_answer": "2.5 litres"
  },
  {
    "question": "A given amount of gas occupies 1000cc at 27\u00b0C and 1200cc and 87\u00b0C. What is its volume coefficient of expansion",
    "correct_answer": "1/273\u00b0 C^-1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A perfect gas at 27\u00b0C heated at constant pressure so as to double its volume. The final temperature of the gas will be",
    "correct_answer": "327\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gas is heated through 1\u00b0C in a closed vessel. Its pressure is increased by 0.4%.\nThe initial temperature of the gas is",
    "correct_answer": "-23\u00b0C"
  },
  {
    "question": "The density of a gas at N.T.P is 1.5 gm/lit, its density at a pressure of 152cm of Hg and temperature 27\u00b0C",
    "correct_answer": "(273/100) gm/ltr"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not thermodynamical function?",
    "correct_answer": "Work done"
  },
  {
    "question": "Thermodynamic system returns to its original state, which of the following is NOT possible?",
    "correct_answer": "The work done is independent of the path followed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Heat is",
    "correct_answer": "Energy in transit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The temperature of a system determines the direction of net change of",
    "correct_answer": "Intermolecular kinetic energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "The thermal motion means",
    "correct_answer": "Random motion of molecules"
  },
  {
    "question": "The mechanical equivalent of heat J is",
    "correct_answer": "A conversion factor"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bullet fired from a gun gets heated on striking a target because",
    "correct_answer": "Mechanical work is converted into heat"
  },
  {
    "question": "A photo electric cell converts",
    "correct_answer": "light energy into electrical energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "The strength of current in photo electric cell",
    "correct_answer": "increases with increase in intensity of incident light"
  },
  {
    "question": "The photoelectric work function",
    "correct_answer": "is different for different metals"
  },
  {
    "question": "In photo electric effect ejection of photo electrons takes place from the surface of metal when",
    "correct_answer": "light of suitable wavelength falls on it"
  },
  {
    "question": "The threshold frequency for potassium is 3\u00d710^14 Hz. The work function is",
    "correct_answer": "2.0 \u00d7 10-^14 J"
  },
  {
    "question": "The photoelectric effect is explained on the basis of",
    "correct_answer": "quantum theory of light"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetization of super conductor is",
    "correct_answer": "-H"
  },
  {
    "question": "Examples of type-I super conductors are",
    "correct_answer": "Al, Zn, Hg"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a super conducting state",
    "correct_answer": "Both entropy and electronic specific heat change"
  },
  {
    "question": "In type-II super conductors the coherence length is of the order of",
    "correct_answer": "10^-3 \u043c"
  },
  {
    "question": "A photo electric cell converts",
    "correct_answer": "light energy into electrical energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "The strength of current in photo electric cell",
    "correct_answer": "increases with increase in intensity of incident light"
  },
  {
    "question": "The photoelectric work function",
    "correct_answer": "is different for different metals"
  },
  {
    "question": "In photo electric effect ejection of photo electrons takes place from the surface of metal when",
    "correct_answer": "light of suitable wavelength falls on it"
  },
  {
    "question": "The threshold frequency for potassium is 3\u00d710^14 Hz. The work function is",
    "correct_answer": "2.0 \u00d7 10-^14 J"
  },
  {
    "question": "The photoelectric effect is explained on the basis of",
    "correct_answer": "quantum theory of light"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetization of super conductor is",
    "correct_answer": "-H"
  },
  {
    "question": "Examples of type-I super conductors are",
    "correct_answer": "Al, Zn, Hg"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a super conducting state",
    "correct_answer": "Both entropy and electronic specific heat change"
  },
  {
    "question": "In type-II super conductors the coherence length is of the order of",
    "correct_answer": "10^-3 \u043c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following quantities have no unit",
    "correct_answer": "Refractive index, strain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Newton Kilogram\u207b\u00b9 is the unit of",
    "correct_answer": "Acceleration"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the minimum number of rectangular components of a vector can be split in space and plane respectively",
    "correct_answer": "3, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the magnitudes of two vectors in dot and cross products are the same then the angle between two vectors",
    "correct_answer": "45\u00b0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two vectors have the same magnitude 'a' and they make an angle '0' with each other. Then magnitude of the resultant is",
    "correct_answer": "2a cos \u03b8/2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bullet is fired with a speed of 200ms\u207b\u00b9 at an angle of 30\u00b0 The height, of a bullet after 5 seconds is",
    "correct_answer": "377.5 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body is falling freely for 't' second. What is its average velocity",
    "correct_answer": "gt/2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A stone is dropped from a balloon which is moving vertically upwards with uniform velocity, when it is at a height 18.4m. If stone touches ground in 4 seconds, find the uniform velocity of balloon.",
    "correct_answer": "15 ms\u207b\u00b9"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ball is dropped on the floor from a height of 10m. It rebounds to a height of 2.5m. If the ball is contact with the floor for 0.01 second and acceleration due to \ngravity g=9.8ms\u207b\u00b2 , its acceleration during contact",
    "correct_answer": "2100 ms\u207b\u00b2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A block sliding initially with a speed of 10ms\u207b\u00b9 on a rough horizontal surface comes to rest at a distance of 50m. The coefficient of kinetic friction if g=10ms\u207b\u00b2",
    "correct_answer": "0.1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 5kg body falls to the ground from a height of 30m. When all its kinetic energy is converted into heat, then the heat produced will be",
    "correct_answer": "1470 J"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two bodies of masses 1 kg and 4 kg are moving with equal kinetic energies. The ratio of their linear moments is",
    "correct_answer": "1:2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bullet travelling with a velocity of \u221a2 ms\u207b\u00b9 pierces a plank of certain thickness and comes to stop. What should be the velocity of bullet to be stopped by double the thickness of the same plank",
    "correct_answer": "2ms\u207b\u00b9"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body of mass 0.1 kg is dropped from a height of 10m at a place where acceleration due to gravity 8=10ms\u207b\u00b2 Its kinetic energy just before striking the ground",
    "correct_answer": "10 joule"
  },
  {
    "question": "The equation for the displacement of a body\nexecuting S.H.M is given by y=2sin[(2\u03c0t/3)-(\u03c0/3)] Then time period of oscillation is",
    "correct_answer": "3 second"
  },
  {
    "question": "The length of the seconds pendulum is 1m. When its period of oscillation is changed to 1.5 second then change in the length of pendulum",
    "correct_answer": "0.4375 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "A body executing simple harmonic motion then what is not the condition for SHM.",
    "correct_answer": "Acceleration and displacements are in opposite direction"
  },
  {
    "question": "In finding reverberation time of an enclosure the formula used is",
    "correct_answer": "T= 0.17A/V"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an experiment, an ideal gas is found to obey an additional law VP\u00b2=constant. The gas is initially at temperature T and Volume V. When it expands to a volume 2V, the temperature becomes",
    "correct_answer": "\u221a2T"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gas at NTP is suddenly compressed to one fourth of its original volume. If y is supposed to be 3/2 final pressure will be",
    "correct_answer": "8 atmosphere"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gas expands under constant pressure P from volume V1 to V2. The work done by the gas is",
    "correct_answer": "P(V2-V1)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The change in internal energy when 400 joule of heat is given to a gas and 100 joule of work is done on it.",
    "correct_answer": "500 joule"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following relation is not a Boyle's law",
    "correct_answer": "P \u03b1 1/d"
  },
  {
    "question": "During photo electric effect, the metallic surface ejects",
    "correct_answer": "Electrons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Optical fibers consists of",
    "correct_answer": "Cladding, Core"
  }
]
}